[
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Shafter?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Eustis?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?",
        "answer": "Indonesia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital city of Paraguay?",
        "answer": "Asuncion"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Acapulco is located in which Mexican state?",
        "answer": "Guerrero"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the Aya Castle?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bical grape originates from which European country?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "West Swan is a suburb in which Australian city?",
        "answer": "Perth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is Dinish Island a part of?",
        "answer": "Ireland"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the Gruta Canabrava cave?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do Vatican City and San Marino have in common?",
        "answer": "Both are landlocked in another country -- Vatican City and San Marino are two of the smallest countries in the world, and they`re both landlocked by Italy."
    },
    {
        "question": "What state is home to the only Bah\u00e1`\u00ed temple in North America?",
        "answer": "Illinois -- Bah\u00e1`\u00ed is a religion that aims to unify all religions and races together as one and promote world peace."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country can you soon walk the world`s longest seafront trail?",
        "answer": "England -- The England Coast Path`s entire path will open in mid-2021, and it will be the world`s longest seafront walking trail."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s longest lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Tanganyika"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Italian city is the namesake of a pasta dish with meat sauce?",
        "answer": "Bologna"
    },
    {
        "question": "The `Pringle` is the nickname for which London landmark?",
        "answer": "The Olympic Velodrome"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before Idaho became a state, which state was almost named Idaho?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state with an official jelly?",
        "answer": "Louisiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Niagara Falls` smallest waterfall?",
        "answer": "Bridal Veil Falls"
    },
    {
        "question": "The name `Sahara` is derived from the Arabic word for what?",
        "answer": "Desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "What prominent University is located in Winston-Salem, North Carolina?",
        "answer": "Wake Forrest"
    },
    {
        "question": "Russia is the world`s largest country (by area), and its largest city (by population) is its capital. What`s the next-largest country for which this is the case?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is `Almost Heaven`?",
        "answer": "West Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country`s flag has the most colors?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states share a border with Quebec?",
        "answer": "Four"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city has a building nicknamed `the Walkie-Talkie building`?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only country with coasts on the Persian Gulf and the Caspian Sea?",
        "answer": "Iran"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mount Teide is the highest mountain in which country?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Slovakia?",
        "answer": "Bratislava"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most westerly capital city in mainland Europe?",
        "answer": "Lisbon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Gambia?",
        "answer": "Banjul"
    },
    {
        "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe River flow?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is Sugarloaf Mountain located in?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a resident of Manchester called?",
        "answer": "Mancunian"
    },
    {
        "question": "In France what is a Framboise?",
        "answer": "Raspberry"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is the Mekong Delta located in?",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which continent would you find the Volga River?",
        "answer": "Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river is often viewed as Russia`s national river?",
        "answer": "Volga"
    },
    {
        "question": "What English city was once known to the Romans as Venta Belgarum?",
        "answer": "Winchester"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state features the one-word motto `Excelsior\u201d?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state features a motto that is a rough translation of its name?",
        "answer": "Texas (`Tejas,` means `allies` or `friends.` The motto of Texas, `Friendship,` is thus a loose translation of the state`s name.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in Scotland is the Queen of England`s Holyroodhouse Palace?",
        "answer": "Edinburgh -- The palace has been home to some of the most renowned figures, from Mary, Queen of Scots to Bonnie Prince Charlie."
    },
    {
        "question": "What geographical feature is a Scottish `loch`?",
        "answer": "Lake -- Scotland has more than 30,000 lakes, including Loch Lomond, its largest lake with a 27.4-square-mile surface area."
    },
    {
        "question": "Poet William Wordsworth wrote a guide to what area that is now a U.K. national park?",
        "answer": "Lake District -- Before it was protected land, the poet wrote in poetic verse `A Guide through the District of the Lakes.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest mountain in the U.K.?",
        "answer": "Ben Nevis -- At 4,412 feet high and located in the Scottish Highlands, Ben Nevis is the U.K.`s tallest mountain."
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is nicknamed `Emerald City`?",
        "answer": "Seattle"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1959, which two territories became US states?",
        "answer": "Alaska and Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Roadrunner is the official bird of which US state?",
        "answer": "New Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for Massachusetts?",
        "answer": "MA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s commercial airport codes all begin with the letter `Y`?",
        "answer": "Canada -- If you`ve booked flights to Vancouver (YVR), Ottawa (YOW), or Montreal (YUL), you may have noticed a consistent theme."
    }
]